citizensfla.com 2019-06-10

# Notice of Privacy Policy - Citizens

###  [Systems Maintenance: Friday, June 14-Sunday, June 16](https://www.citizensfla.com/alerts)

General

### Systems Maintenance: Friday, June 14-Sunday, June 16

Citizens' policy systems, including electronic payments and payments by phone, will not be available due to maintenance on Friday, June 14, from 6 p.m. to Sunday, June 16, at 6 p.m. Report a loss by contacting our 24/7, toll-free Claims Reporting Center at 866.411.2742 during this time. We apologize for any inconvenience.

FACTS

WHAT DOES CITIZENS PROPERTY INSURANCE CORPORATION DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?

Why?

Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.

What?

The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include: 

  * Social Security number
  * Information you provide on your application for insurance coverage, such as your name, address, telephone number, date of birth, and occupation
  * Information gathered from you as our insured, your payment history, type of coverage you have, underwriting information, and claims information
  * Credit card or bank account information
  * Mortgage information
  * Information from your visits to [www.citizensfla.com](http://www.citizensfla.com/)

How?

All financial companies need to share customers' personal information to run their everyday business. Citizens uses your personal information only as authorized or required by law and as necessary to provide our products and services to you. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customers' personal information; the reasons Citizens chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.

Reasons we can share your personal information

Does Citizens share?

Can you limit this sharing?

For our everyday business purposes-We share with non affiliates to assist us to process your transactions, underwrite and/or rate your policy, service your policy, administer claims, respond to court orders and legal investigations, and as permitted by federal and state law.

Yes

No

For our marketing purposes-to offer our products and services to you

No

We don't share

For joint marketing with other financial companies

No

We don't share

For our affiliates' everyday business purposes-information about your transactions and experiences

No

We don't share

For our affiliates' everyday business purposes-information about your creditworthiness

No

We don't share

For non affiliates to market to you

No

We don't share

Questions?

Call 866.411.2742; Deaf/Hard of Hearing: 800.955.8771 (TTY) or 800.955.8770 (Voice); or go to [www.citizensfla.com](http://www.citizensfla.com/)

How does Citizens protect my personal information?

To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings. Our employees and vendors are authorized to access information only for valid business reasons. They must agree in writing to maintain the confidentiality of non public personal information. We do not share medical information unless authorized by you or as required by law.

How does Citizens collect my personal information?

We collect your personal information, for example, when: 

  * you apply for insurance
  * we process your application
  * you pay insurance premiums
  * you give us your contact information
  * you give information to your agent or property inspector
  * you file an insurance claim (or if a claim is made against you)
  * you show us your government-issued ID or driver's license
  * you visit Citizens' website if you voluntarily provide the information

We also collect information from other companies, such as your loss history.

Why can't I limit all sharing?

Federal law gives you the right to limit only: 

  * sharing for affiliates' everyday business purposes-information about your creditworthiness
  * affiliates from using your information to market to you
  * sharing for non affiliates to market to you

State law and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing. See below for more on your rights under state law.

Affiliates

Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies. 

  * Citizens has no affiliates

Non affiliates

Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial or nonfinancial company. Non affiliates we share with can include: 

  * Independent insurance agents and agencies
  * Independent adjusters or claims representatives
  * Inspection companies
  * Auditors
  * Insurance support organizations
  * Attorneys, courts, and government agencies

Joint marketing

A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you. 

  * Citizens does not jointly market

Other important information

State law - The Florida public records law requires that all information received by a state entity be made available to anyone upon request, including e-mail addresses, unless the information is subject to a specific statutory exemption.

The Public Records Custodian can be contacted at:

> **Public Records Custodian**  
>  Citizens Property Insurance Corporation  
>  2101 Maryland Circle  
>  Tallahassee, FL 32303  

Node: cit-lryasjax302
